Joshua Korner-Godsiff

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

12/19 Crane St, Homebush, NSW, Australia, 2140

□ 0408 125 562 | ■ josh.godsiff@gmail.com | □ joshgodsiff | □ joshgodsiff

About Myself_____

I'm Josh. I'm a software developer with around 7 years of commercial experience, and I currently live and work in Sydney.

For most of 2020 I have been working on my own startup in the digital identity space. However, due to some significant life events I'm putting that on the back-burner for a few years and hopping back into the job market.

My expertise is in large-scale data processing pipelines and functional programming, and I have extensive experience doing web development. I'm also passionate about privacy, civil liberties, and the environment.

For my next role I'm looking for something where I can step up and take on more responsibility. In particular, a role where I can work across both software development and product management would be ideal.

I graduated from the Australian National University in 2014 with a Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours) - one of their most challenging and selective degrees.

At university I focused on large scale parallel and distributed systems; various machine learning, data mining and AI techniques; and a healthy dose of pure theory and mathematics.

Skills

Programming Haskell, Scala, Java, JavaScript, Python, SQL

Document / Data Formats HTML & CSS, XML, Avro, JSON

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, Kafak, ElasticSearch

Libraries & Frameworks React, Angular, Hedgehog, Amazonka, Lens, MTL

Cloud Platforms AWS

Operating Systems
Tools & Software
Soft Skills
Soft Skills
Windows, Ubuntu Linux, MacOS
VSCode, JetBrains IDEs, Git, Terraform
Agile, Product Management, Mentoring

Experience _____

1Self Sydney, Australia

Co-Founder February 2020 - Present

As a co-founder I worked across all functions of the business, with a particular focus on software development, product management, and legal and compliance issues.

Netscout (formerly Arbor Networks)

Sydney, Australia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

January 2017 - January 2020

At Netscout I worked as part of an agile team to deliver scalable data processing pipelines that power a suite of analytics tools and services which are used by both their customers, and their sales and support teams.

My team and I were responsible for almost all aspects of these pipelines, including development, deployment, monitoring, end-to-end-testing, and working with our product and delivery management team to clarify goals and scope work.

I primarily worked in Haskell for development, with some forays into Scala (legacy pipelines), Ruby & Terraform (deployment & infrastructure tooling), Python (ML code, scripting), and even occasional bits of C and JavaScript.

I learned an incredible amount, especially about what it takes to develop and deploy stable, scalable, and maintainable solutions. I also greatly enjoyed some of my secondary duties, which included leading internal workshops on Haskell and functional programming, as well as mentoring interns in some fundamental computer-science concepts.

General Dynamics Mediaware

Canberra, Australia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER October 2015 - December 2016

At Mediaware I worked as part of an agile team to help deliver mission critical video processing software to our defence and broadcast customers around the globe.

My primary responsibility was leading the development and design of the web-based user interfaces to our core products. These used a purpose-built Python + KnockoutJS framework, as many of the products had real-time constraints that required a careful interaction model. Later in the role I also introduced a more traditional AngularJS + Python stack for a separate project.

My secondary responsibilities included working with senior architects on system design, liaising with key stakeholders to gather requirements and feedback, and producing reports to inform business level decision making.

I also dove into the main server applications (C/C++) from time to time to implement the relevant endpoints and data sources for the UI.

Welcomer Canberra, Australia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

October 2014 - July 2015

My role at Welcomer was as a full-stack developer. I was primarily responsible for building and maintaining our application's front-end structure and logic using Angular JS, as well as its associated test-suites and build-system.

I also spent some of my time delving into the our backend framework to make changes to our JSON API as needed. The backend was custom built software written in Scala + Akka, and backed by Mongo.

Australian National University

Canberra, Australia

Tutor

February 2012 - June 2015 (Part time)

I worked as a tutor during the first semesters of 2012, 2013, and 2015, teaching the "Introduction to Programming and Algorithms" course.

My duties included tutoring groups of 10-20 first year students on programming; marking assignments; administering tests; and participating in weekly meetings in order to manage the course's operation and content.

Oxide Interactive

Canberra, Australia

January 2010 - September 2010

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Zoo Advertising

Canberra, Australia

WEB DEVELOPER (CONTRACTOR)

March 2009 - September 2009

The Stavridis Group

Canberra, Australia

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

November 2008 - February 2009

Education

Australian National University

Canberra, Australia

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (HONOURS) - FIRST CLASS HONOURS

2009 - 2014

The Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours) is a four year undergraduate degree taught in English. The degree is a research-focused professional program for exceptional students who have an interest in undertaking research in an industry or academic environment. It is expected that students will graduate with First Class Honours.

Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours) students are expected to maintain a superior distinction average in order to remain in the degree.

An academic transcript is available upon request.

General Assembly

Sydney, Australia

PRODUCT MANAGEMENT - 1 WEEK INTENSIVE

2019

A one week intensive course on product management, covering topics such as the product lifecycle, hypothesis validation, customer interviews, personas, feature prioritisation, competitor research, minimum viable products, product roadmaps, metrics, sketching, wireframes, usability testing, and agile.

Community Involvement

International Conference on Functional Programming

ATTENDEE 2019

Lambda Jam Sydney, Australia

Attendee, Speaker 2017, 2018

In 2018 I gave a talk on "The Human Side of Haskell"

PyConAUMelbourne, Australia

ATTENDEE 2016

Functional Programming MeetupCanberra & Sydney, Australia

GROUP MEMBER 2016 - Present

Lean Beer MeetupCanberra & Sydney, Australia

FOUNDING MEMBER 2016 - Present

A fortnightly meetup on Agile, Lean, project management, software development, & startups

Presentations _____

Lambda Jam Sydney, Australia

THE HUMAN SIDE OF HASKELL 2018

✓ YouTube - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z0vkQLLUVGw

Berlin, Germany